

About

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web app deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with thech trends.

In the past three years I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

Work Experience

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on the high perormance security projects. Created automated tests through bash, Perl and the in-house tools. I also developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment. Worked with a large multinational team

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on socio-political issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

Education

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

September 2013 - Present

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and consumption of web content, database technologies.

Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer Architectures Low-level programing. Software Engineering - principles and lifecycle, scalability and maintnance.

Team projects, working as part of a group.

Website plamen-k.github.io
Email p.kolev22@gmail.com
Github https://github.com/plamen-k

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

Projects

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a website for the neven brand

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

Presenter at Lester College conference that taught the importance of writing secure code

Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the british bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU.

Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

PAConsulting

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and controll.

Webloz

18 April 2012

Webloz -national competition for web development finalist